All pirates must die.
Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Men Tell No Tales is a adventure,
action, fantasy film directed by Espen Sandberg.
Thrust into an all-new adventure, a down-on-his-luck Capt.
Jack Sparrow feels the winds of ill-fortune blowing even more strongly when
deadly ghost sailors led by his old nemesis, the evil Capt.
Salazar, escape from the Devil's Triangle.
Jack's only hope of survival lies in seeking out the legendary Trident of Poseidon, but to find it, he must forge an
uneasy alliance with a brilliant and beautiful astronomer and a headstrong young man in the British navy.
Jack Sparrow, played by Johnny Depp.
Armando Salazar, played by Javier Bardem.
Hector Barbossa, played by Geoffrey Rush.
Henry Turner, played by Brenton Thwaites.
Carina Smyth, played by Kaya Scodelario.
Shansa, played by Golshifteh Farahani.
Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Men Tell No Tales (released in some territories as Pirates of the Caribbean: Salazar's Revenge) is a 2017
American swashbuckler fantasy film that is the fifth in the Pirates of the Caribbean film series, following On Stranger Tides (2011).
The film was directed by Joachim Rønning and Espen
Sandberg and written by Jeff Nathanson.
It features an ensemble cast including Johnny Depp, Javier Bardem, Geoffrey
Rush, Brenton Thwaites, Kaya Scodelario, and Kevin McNally.
The film follows a search for the Trident of Poseidon by a down-on-his-luck Captain Jack Sparrow pursued by Captain Armando Salazar and a crew
of deadly ghosts who have escaped from the Devil's Triangle, determined to kill every pirate at sea and take revenge on Sparrow.
Development of the film started shortly before the previous film was released in May 2011, with
Rossio writing the initial script, and Depp being involved in the writing process.
In early 2013, Nathanson was hired to write a new script, while Rønning and
Sandberg became involved in the project shortly afterward.
The filmmakers cited the series' first installment, The Curse of the Black
Pearl (2003), as inspiration for the script and tone of the film.
Initially planned for a 2015 release, the film was delayed to 2016
and then to 2017, due to script and budget issues.
Principal photography started in Queensland, Australia in February 2015, after the Australian
government offered Disney $20 million in tax incentives, and ended that July.
With an estimated production budget  of $230–320 million, it
is among the most expensive films ever made.
Dead Men Tell No Tales premiered at the Shanghai Disney Resort on May 11,
2017, and was released in the United States on May 26.
The film received generally negative reviews from
critics and grossed $796 million.
The film explores themes of treasure map, artifact, pirate, swashbuckler, ghost.